Dorothea A. Dreier
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Printed Materials, circa 1883-1941, Series 3:; (Boxes 2-3; 0.5 linear feet
  Newspaper clippings record the artistic, social and political activities of the Dreier family as well as other subjects of interest to Dorothea. A folder of pamphlets and broadsides provide information concerning the political, social and charitable causes that Dorothea supported, including the Home for Recreation of Woman and Children that her mother founded in 1898 as the German Home for Women and Children. Finally there is a collection of postcards assembled from her travels.
  In most cases, only the cover and title page of exhibition catalogs, brochures and pamphlets have been scanned. Blank postcards, general travel materials, and clippings, brochures and advertisements unrelated to the Dreiers or their interests, have not been scanned.
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1911-1941 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Exhibition Catalog: The Dorothea A. Dreier Exhibition, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Clippings concerning Dorothea A. Dreier, 1921-1925 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Clippings concerning Other Dreier Family Members, circa 1912-1916 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Clippings, Illustrations of New York, New York, circa 1910-1915 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Clippings, Art, circa 1910-1916.0 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Clippings, Political Topics, circa 1912-1914 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Clippings, General, circa 1910-1916, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Pamphlets and Broadsides, 1887-1914 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 1)
  - General Brochures and Advertisements, circa 1883-1916, (Not scanned) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 2)
  - General Travel Materials, circa 1906-1916, (Not scanned) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 3)
  - Blank Postcards, before 1923, (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 4-6)
- Photographs, circa 1900-1923, Series 4:; (Box 3; 7 folders)
  Photographs in this series include studio portraits and informal photographs of Dorothea and Katherine Dreier, group photographs, and a reproduction of a painting by Katherine S. Dreier. There is also a folder of vintage photographs, many of which appear to have been taken in the Netherlands. This group of general photographs also includes several snapshots that seem to document a speech given by Theodore Roosevelt at a railway station.
  A photographic postcard of a painting by Katherine S. Dreier was not scanned.
  - Dorothea A. Dreier, circa 1885-1923, (3 folders; 18 vintage prints) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 7-9)
  - Dorothea A. Dreier with Others, circa 1900-1923, (10 vintage prints) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 10)
  - Katherine S. Dreier, circa 1910-1920, (6 vintage prints) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 11)
  - General Photographs, circa 1900-1923, (47 vintage prints) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 12)
  - Works of Art, undated, (Not scanned) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 13)
- Artwork, circa 1885 - 1941, Series 5:; (Box 3; 9 Folders)
  Items in this series include sketchbooks, a matted graphite drawing and two prints. Only one item, an undated sketchbook of botanical drawings, is the work of Dorothea Dreier. There is a sketchbook titled L.S.S. by an unidentified artist that includes pencil sketches done aboard the transatlantic liner the S.S. Lahn and locations across Western Europe in the summer of 1901. Finally there are five sketchbooks belonging to friend and teacher Walter Shirlaw containing pencil, watercolor and crayon sketches that suggest designs for mural paintings. There is also a matted pencil drawing of a toad that Shirlaw has inscribed "Dorothea Dreir's Coat of Arms, The Biggest Toad in the Puddle." Finally prints include an undated Huquier engraving from several studies of dogs by Sneyders and Ernest D. Roth's 1941 etching for the Friends of the Brooklyn Public Library.
  - Dorothera A. Dreier Sketchbook, undated (Box 3 (hol), Folder 14)
  - Sketchbook "L.S.S.," 1901 (Box 4 (pam), Folder 1)
  - Walter Shirlaw Sketchbooks, before 1909, (5 folders; 5 sketchbooks) (Box 4 (pam), Folder 2-6)
  - Walter Shirlaw Artwork, circa 1903-1904 (Box 4 (pam), Folder 7)
    (includes a drawing, The Biggest Toad in the Puddle, and a watercolor of a turkey)
  - Prints by Other Artists, 1941 and undated (Box 4 (pam), Folder 8)